I simply can't
我根本就没有办法
focus on my work.
认真工作
Chores, work,
我忙完了家里 忙工作
I don't even get a moment
我一刻喘息的机会
to breathe.
都没有
I can't say
我知道
I'm the best husband
我不是世界上
in the world,
最好的丈夫
but I'm close enough.
但我也差不多
For you,
为了你
and your family,
为了你们家人
I spend money and effort.
出钱出力
You are my top priority.
永远冲在最前面
Your requests,
你的要求
I try my best to satisfy them.
我尽量地去满足
But look how you treat me,
可你怎么对我的
and my family.
你怎么对我家人的
Bullying me, I put up with it,
你欺负我就算了
but why did you bully my mom?
连我妈你一起欺负
I didn't get married
我娶媳妇
to put my mom into suffering.
让我妈跟着受气啊
You're a good daughter to your mom.
你是你妈好闺女
I also want to serve mine right!
我是我妈好儿子吗
Indeed, childbirth is tough.
是 你生孩子辛苦
To make it easier for you,
为了让你轻松点
I hired a costly nanny.
花那么多的钱 请月嫂
But you insulted her,
你羞辱她
and me.
羞辱我
You cast shame
你让我们全家脸
on my whole family!
往哪儿搁
It's not me. It's postpartum depression
我 我就是产后抑郁嘛
and I've already seen a therapist,
我已经去看心理医生了
Haowen.
浩文
It's too late.
晚了
I...
我
I'm too tired!
我太累了
Exhausted, really.
真的 我太累了
I flatter you,
我每天哈着你
day after day.
哄着你
I praise you,
捧着你
and I do everything as you say.
什么都听你的
I've lost my dignity.
我没有尊严
I've lost myself.
我也没有脸
Days feel too long,
日子那么长
but life is too short.
人生又那么短
Do I deserve to live like this?
我就这么活着
Do I?
我值不值得啊
Xu Mengxin,
许梦心
I'm worn out.
我累不累啊
I'm sick of this.
我受得了吗
I'll change, Haowen.
我改 浩文
I don't want to
我不想再有
keep living like this.
这样的日子了
I want to live for myself.
我想为我自己活着
Haowen, Haowen, Haowen!
浩文 浩文 浩文
Think about the kids!
你不要我 不要孩子啦
Haowen!
浩文
Haowen, Haowen!
浩文 浩文
Haowen,
浩文你别走好不好
I'm begging you.
我求求你了
Just let me fix it.
你再给我一次机会
I'll do whatever you say, I...
我一定都听你的 我
Hao,
浩
Haowen!
浩文
How did you know
你怎么知道
it's my birthday today?
我今天生日啊
Magic,
我神通广大
I know everything.
什么都知道
Ms Chen Wanzhen,
陈婉真小姐
happy birthday.
祝你生日快乐
Dr. Yu,
俞医生
I'd like to thank you
我要谢谢你
for these carefully prepared gifts.
精心给我准备这些礼物
Especially, I want to thank you for
尤其要谢谢你平时
taking care of my two children.
对我两个孩子的照顾
You don't have to
可不可以
call me Dr. Yu.
不要再叫我俞医生
Yu Chen is OK.
叫我俞辰就好了
I'm used to calling you Dr. Yu.
叫俞医生已经叫习惯了
I just feel that
我只是觉得
it makes us seem distant.
这么叫显得我们很生分
Wanzhen,
婉真
I hope I can become
我希望可以成为
someone close to you in your life.
你生命当中亲近的人
I know
我知道
I should be more patient.
现在可能有点快
but I think
但是我觉得
we can start as friends.
我可以先从朋友做起
Dr. Yu,
俞医生
let's make a wish together.
我们一起许个愿吧
OK.
好
Close your eyes,
闭上眼睛
and imagine the next five or ten years.
想一想未来五年 十年
What will you be doing?
你在做什么
What will I be doing?
我在做什么
Close your eyes and think carefully.
闭上眼睛好好想一想
I see you
我看到
in my future,
我的未来里有你
and Wanwan and Zhenzhen too.
还有婉婉 真真
In ten years,
十年以后
I'll be an attending doctor.
我是主治大夫
You'll become
你成了
a powerful
叱咤风云的
top-tier manager lady.
头号女经理人
We'll be living in a big house,
我们住在一栋大房子里
working hard together
一起为了我们的生活
for our future.
努力地奋斗
Wanzhen?
婉真
I'm sorry, Dr. Yu.
对不起 俞医生
I'm about to enter
我即将踏入
the second half of my life.
人生的下半场
I don't want any more changes.
我不想人生再有变化
There's not much room
我的未来里
for many people in my future,
住不下太多人
just me and my
只有我和我的
Wanwan and Zhenzhen.
婉婉 真真
The 32nd Chinese Medical Team
中国第三十二批
to assist Africa
援非医疗队
is recruiting pediatricians.
招募儿科医生
The work period is 18 months.
工作期十八个月
Is anyone signing up?
有人报名吗
Pregnancy is so food-consuming!
怀孕要吃这么多东西啊
I don't even know how much
也不知道有多少
actually benefits the baby.
能补到孩子身上
My weight is surely
反正我最近这肉
shooting up.
是蹭蹭蹭地往上长
Xu Meng'an
许梦安
Xu Meng'an, come out!
许梦安 你出来
Where are you?
人呢
Who's there?
谁呀
Xu Meng'an, get out!
滚出来 许梦安
What's this shouting all about?
干吗呀 你嚷嚷什么呀
So uncivilized.
这么没有素质
Uncivilized?
没素质
That's for her!
没素质的人是她
What's the matter?
什么事啊
Did you
你是不是
report Xinmiao?
把新苗给举报了
Report?
举报
What happened to Xinmiao?
新苗怎么了
There has been a talk
刚刚被约谈了
that our Xinmiao company
说是我们新苗公司
is canceled online for rectification.
无限期地封号 整改
Was it you?
是不是你
Did you report us?
是你举报的吗
Or did you instruct someone else to do it?
还是你指使其他人干的
You think it was me, don't you?
你也觉得是我干的
You were the only one
拉新方案
who opposed the user acquisition plan.
就你一个人反对
You were the one that
就你一天到晚
kept saying it was against regulations.
叫着违规操作
If it wasn't you, then who?
不是你还有谁
I'm the company's content director,
我是公司的内容总监
why would I report my own company?
我会举报自己的公司吗
Precisely! Because you're an insider,
自己人
you know well how to frame us.
所以正中要害
Mr. Zhang,
张总
I kept telling you
我早就说过
not to challenge the regulations.
你们踏线操作是不行的
But you didn't listen!
但是你们不听啊
Now that
现在怎么了
things went wrong,
出事了
do not try to
想甩锅啊
shift the blame on me!
我不背的
I do this all for the company!
我这么做是为了公司
The company!
好吗
You filed the report,
你举报告发
and I don't know why.
你是为了什么呀
Did you want to ruin me?
你是想毁了我
Or ruin Xinmiao?
还是想毁了新苗
All for the company?
你是为了公司吗
You did this only for yourself!
你是为了你自己
Mr. Zhang, I swear
张总 这件事情
I didn't file the report.
肯定不是我做的
If someone did report it,
如果说举报的话
there are too many possible suspects
那真的 人太多了
new users, old users,
新用户 老用户
and competitor companies.
还有竞品公司
For such operations,
这种操作
a report is a sure thing.
一报一个准的
If it were a competitor company,
竞品公司举报
there must've been an insider,
那也是要有内鬼
leaking the information.
通风报信的
Otherwise, how could they
不然人家
know so well
怎么对我们的事情
of our business?
知道得那么清楚
Talking about a mole?
说内鬼是吧
Go check with your outsourcing team.
找你外包团队去
There is a whole room of them.
一屋子人呢
Deputy Director Huang,
黄副总监啊
let's speak with evidence.
说话还是要讲证据的
That's right, evidence!
没错 证据
Xu Meng'an,
许梦安
prove your innocence!
自证清白吧
Mr. Zhang,
张总
investigate her.
查她
I apply for a freeze on
我要求查封她的
all her social media accounts.
所有社交平台账号
Confiscate her phone,
上交她的手机
computer and iPad.
电脑 平板电脑
And find out
还有
all her personal
她所有社交平台的
social media passwords.
个人账号密码
She must be investigated!
必须查她
My tolerance for you is running out!
老娘真的忍你很久了
What do you want from me?
你想干吗你
What do you want?
想干吗
Easy! Easy!
别打 别打
Director Xu,
许总监
for the sake of your fetus!
您别忘了 怀着孕
How dare you hit me?
你有什么权力打我呢
A pregnant lady needs protection!
保护孕妇
Hurry, hurry!
你快点 快点
She's pregnant!
她是孕妇
That is exactly
这就是孕妇
why we must stop her!
你才得拦着 你傻不傻
Come on and try me!
你上来试试
Mr. Zhang, don't!
张总 你别
Mr. Zhang!
张总
Are you alright, Mr. Zhang?
张总 没事吧 张总
No, thanks.
不喝
Just tell me how you plan to deal with me.
说吧 想怎么处理我
What plan?
处理什么呀
You...
你这这这
you gave us
你 原来没看出来
quite a surprise.
你说这
You shouldn't have hit her.
你怎么还敢动手呢
If she had fought back,
那她万一还手了
your fetus,
你这肚子里孩子
it would've been a mess!
你说怎么弄
She wouldn't dare!
她敢
She did say something quite offensive.
她说那话确实挺过分的
If it were me, I'd scratch her too.
要我 我也挠她
Oh, just give it a rest.
你可得了吧 你啊
I told you to stop her,
刚才让你拦着点
and you didn't.
你都不拦
Well, you didn't stop her either.
那也没见您拦哪
You have let her vent a little.
你不得让她出口气呀
Vent?
出气是吧
I'm telling you, if she's injured
我告诉你出出事了
and goes to a medical exam,
她那个验伤去了
she might sue you.
可能要讹你啊
Then I'll resign.
那我就辞职呗
She craves my position anyway.
她不就想要我这位置吗
Just give it to her.
你给她不就完了吗
You are really
我发现你一聊天
a conversation killer!
就把天给聊死了
Why are you so temperamental?
你那么大脾气呢
I have high pregnancy hormones.
我孕激素高
I still won't let you resign.
你高了我也不同意
Well, I disagree too.
那我也不同意
The contract isn't up yet.
这合同还没到期呢
Then I'll take a long leave.
那我休长假行了吧
I'm near the time of labor,
反正我现在月份也大了
and the company is under rectification,
公司也整改了
no need for me to be here.
不用我干什么了
You still have two deputy directors.
你不还有两副总监呢吗
Let them handle it.
你让她们弄吧
Let's discuss it after my maternity leave.
我休完产假再说
Alright, fine.
可以
I...
我
She has her point.
那本来就是嘛
No pregnant woman
哪有孕妇像她这样的
should go to work every day
天天挺个大肚子
and withstand such
过来上班
humiliation.
还受这样的气
Staying at home with her kid,
人家在家陪陪孩子
this is much better.
不香啊
You,
我跟你说
you just made things worse!
公司黄了全是你搅和的
Well, now you are panicking.
您 您现在着急了
Huang Sisi, she messed up
你说这黄思思把这事
the whole thing.
给搅和成这样
I say it is better
是不是
to have some evidence.
咱得拿出证据来呀
Right?
是吧
You need to prove yourself innocent.
你得自证清白
Reputation is vital.
名声还是很重要的
Just go home and rest a few days.
你先回去休息两天
After you are calm down,
消了气啊
please hurry back.
赶紧回来
We all count on you
这边一大摊子事
to deal with this mess.
都指望着你
Let's try something different
我们今天的康复训练呢
in today's rehabilitation training.
改变一种形式
To train your coordination,
为了训练你的协调性
we'll start learning
我们今天开始学习
the most basic steps
中国舞蹈的
of Chinese dance.
最基本的舞步
The Yangge dance.
秧歌步
I'll demonstrate first.
我先给你们示范一下
In early spring,
二月里来
four five six seven...
四五六七
It's a bit difficult.
有点难
Oh, I see.
难吗
Alright, then we'll
好 那我们
switch to an easier one.
下面换一个简单的啊
It's super easy.
非常简单
Now I begin.
预备 开始
One two three four.
一二三四
That's it!
对
This will do.
这行
Six seven eight,
六七八
two three four, five six seven eight.
二三四 五六七八
Four two three four
四二三四
five six seven...
五六七
Uncle, you feel tired?
叔 你累啦
Senior, it's too early
老爷子 快快快 快起来
to rest now!
再练会儿
Come.
来来来
Hold on.
坚持一下
You know
坚持 坚持
persistence is victory!
坚持就是胜利
Ready? Let's begin.
来 预备 开始
One two three four.
一二三四
Good, and five!
对 五
Great!
真好 真
Why don't you teach him?
你 你教他吧
Are you loafing?
你摸鱼呢
That's right.
对
Keep it this way.
来来来 你跳
And four
四 来
five six seven eight.
五六七八
Clap your hands! One
拍手 一
two two three four five six seven eight.
二二三四 五六七八
That's it.
对了
Three two three four five six seven eight.
三二三四 五六七八
Mind the rhythm!
节奏 节奏
One two three four, five six.
一二三四 五六
Meng'an.
梦安
You're dancing!
跳上了
Yes.
对
Do you like it?
行不行啊
Wow,
你
why are you back so early?
你怎么这么早就回来了
I take a leave.
公司给我放假了
You should've rested earlier.
早应该放假了
With your pregnancy,
你看你肚子都这么大
rest is a must.
早该休息了
Where is Xin?
心心呢
She went to see a therapist.
她去看心理医生去了
She should've been back by now.
她早该回来了呀
Where did she go?
上哪儿去了
Harmony is vital for a family.
家和万事兴
You cause trouble every day.
你每天闹得鸡犬不宁
I simply can't
我根本就没有办法
focus on my work.
认真工作
Why are you two here?
你俩怎么来这儿了
Let me introduce you
我给你们介绍一下
to Lili, the blogger.
这是博主 丽丽姐
I'm his wife. Who are you?
我是他老婆 你谁呀
Xin, there's a misunderstanding.
心 你误会了 心
Jia Haowen, get out.
贾浩文 出去
Me getting out?
叫谁出去呢
It's you who should leave my husband!
你跟我老公在一个房间
I'm all yours.
我人都是你的
Listen,
你想
you're carrying my baby,
咱们家的二宝贝
our second child.
还在你的肚子里呢
How could I ever
我怎么可能沾花惹草
cheat on you?
偷鸡摸狗呢
Impossible!
不可能
Are you saying that if I die,
是不是我死了
you'll find someone else?
你就可以找别人了
Tell me!
说
Tell me or you won't get to sleep!
你今天要不说别想睡觉
Where are you going?
上哪儿去啊
Work staff.
公司有事
I'll be right back.
我马上回来啊
Jia Haowen!
贾浩文
I'll be right back,
姑奶奶 我马上就回来
honey.
宝贝
Don't come back!
你别回来了
I can't say
我不是世界上
I'm the best husband in the world,
最好的丈夫
but I'm close enough.
但我也差不多
For you,
为了你
and your family,
为了你们家人
I spend money and effort.
出钱出力
You are my top priority.
永远冲在最前面
Your requests,
你的要求
I try my best to satisfy them.
我尽量地去满足
You're a good daughter to your mom.
你是你妈好闺女
I also want to serve my mom right!
我是我妈好儿子吗
Look how you treat my family,
你怎么对我家人的
Bullying me, I put up with it,
你欺负我就算了
but why did you bully my mom?
连我妈你一起欺负
Haowen should come back
让老贾回来带
and take care of his own daughter.
带他亲女儿
Don't work anymore.
别上班了
You are mutton dressed as lamb,
您不光装嫩
pretending to
您还装出一副
care about me.
很关心我的样子
But really, you only care about
你每天就知道
your granddaughter.
我孙女好不好
How well did she eat,
我孙女今天吃得怎么样
drink,
我孙女今天睡得怎么样
and sleep.
我孙女今天喝得好不好
It's always about your granddaughter.
我孙女 我孙女 我孙女
Have you ever cared about me?
你孙女她妈你关心过吗
All you do every day
你每天就知道
is pamper your granddaughter.
哄着你孙女
What about me?
我呢 我呢
Do you even see me?
你眼里有我吗
I didn't get married
我娶媳妇
to put my mom into suffering.
让我妈跟着受气啊
You insulted her
你羞辱她
and me.
羞辱我
You cast shame
你让我们全家脸
on my whole family!
往哪儿搁
Xin,
心心啊
Xin!
心心
Why are you standing here?
你站这儿干吗呀
Why did you leave
你怎么出来
without telling us?
也不跟家里人说一声啊
I'm worried about you.
姐担心你呢
Haowen abandoned me.
老贾不要我了
Don't be silly.
怎么会呢
Haowen wouldn't do that.
老贾怎么会不要你呢
He wants a divorce.
他要跟我离婚
What should I do?
怎么办呀
What can I do?
我怎么办啊
No, that won't happen.
不会的 不会的
That won't happen.
不会的啊
Don't worry.
不会的
He abandoned me, sis.
他不要我了 姐
He abandoned me.
他不要我了
I won't.
姐要
Now that we've inspected the projects,
几个项目都看完了
let's have a few words.
聊两句
Alright.
好啊
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Are today's projects
今天这几个项目
worth investing in?
值不值得投
What do you think?
你觉得呢
I'm the boss here.
我是老板 你是老板
I'm asking for your opinion.
我在问你的意见
I just want to see
我是想看看
if my thoughts
我的想法跟你的想法
align with yours.
是不是一致
I want to know it too.
我也想知道
Whether our thoughts
我的想法跟你的想法
align.
一不一致
I'm the boss.
我是老板
I have this right, don't I?
我有这个权力吧
Of course.
当然了
I just try to make a test
我是想试试自己的水平
to see if we are on the same level.
跟你是不是齐平
If so,
如果齐平的话
then in the future,
那我以后
I can make decisions on my own.
就可以自己做主了
Want to be a big woman?
翅膀越来越硬了
I've noticed that lately,
我发现你最近
you've been very confident.
非常自信啊
A bit too much, maybe?
有点飘啊
Thanks to your influence.
那不是受你的影响吗
No matter how plain you are,
不管自己是否普通
you have to be very confident.
那都要非常自信
Am I plain?
我普通吗
Alright, alright.
好了 好了
I won't play the boss here.
我也不给你摆老板的谱
To be fair,
公平起见
let's write down our opinions separately,
咱俩同时写各自的看法
and then exchange them.
然后同时交换看
Sounds good.
好啊
Write in detail, though.
那个 写得详细一点啊
Include the reasons
把说服我的理由
to convince me.
也得写进去
Actually, I already wrote something.
其实我之前写了一些
Let me adjust it.
我调整一下
Looks like our thoughts
看来咱俩的想法
are surprisingly aligned again.
又是惊人的一致
Alright,
那行
let's move forward
就照目前这个方向
in this direction,
我们往下推进
and refine the report.
再细化这个报告
OK.
好
By the way,
对了
I have a meeting
我一会儿约了一个
with a startup boss.
创业公司的老总过来
Would you like to join us?
要不要一起聊一聊
New agenda?
还有行程安排啊
It was a last-minute arrangement.
临时安排的
Do you have plans?
怎么了 有事啊
I promised a video call with the kids.
我是约了跟孩子视频
It's alright.
没事
I'll reschedule it.
我来调整一下
No, kids come first.
别别 孩子事是大事
Work can wait.
工作不重要
Go ahead with your call.
那你先去视频去吧
Stop with that.
少来这一套
I'll go call the kids now,
我现在就去跟孩子视频
and be right back.
马上回来
Ms. Chen Wanzhen,
陈婉真女士
Hello.
你好
There are two guests,
两位客人啊
claiming to be your best friends,
说是您最好的朋友
would like to see you.
想要见您
My best friends?
我最好的朋友
I want to have a video call with
我要跟婉婉 真真
Wanwan and Zhenzhen.
通视频电话
why aren't you answering?
你怎么不接呢
Tell me
你告诉我
who they're with right now.
她们现在和谁在一起
I'll come...
我现在就
Mom!
妈妈
My babies.
宝贝
You...
你们
Mom!
妈妈
It's our birthday.
我们的生日
You've worked so hard for us.
你最辛苦了
Mom, we love you.
妈妈 我们爱你
Dad told us that.
爸爸跟我们说的
Don't think I'm cheesy.
你别嫌我俗啊
Happy birthday, little beauties.
两位小美女 生日快乐
Thank you, Uncle Zhou.
谢谢周叔叔
Surprised? Happy?
意不意外 开不开心
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Happy birthday to you.
祝你们生日快乐
Mr. Zhou,
周总
thank you.
谢谢你啊
If it weren't for your help,
如果 没有您的帮助
I wouldn't have been able to fulfill my wish.
我也完不成我这个心愿
Don't mention it.
不用客气
I did it
我是为了让温蒂
to cheer Wendy up.
开心一点
So she can work
这样她工作起来
with more enthusiasm.
更有劲头
By the way, Mr. Yu,
对了 于总
I heard about the rectification of Xinmiao,
我听说新苗被监管了
which makes Blue Ocean
蓝海传媒
the company
又重新回到了
with most users, again.
市用户量第一
Tell me,
说说
what exactly did you do?
你到底做了什么
Nothing.
我什么都没做啊
Normal operation, that's all.
这就是无为而治
I never expected
也没想到
that our competitor
我们的竞争对手
would fall.
会翻车
It's a windfall to us.
所以才成全了我们蓝海
You really didn't do anything?
你真的什么都没做
Xinmiao's current strategy
新苗现在的策略
is nothing new
其实都是
than the one
我们之前
we used many years ago.
多少年就用过的
In the short term,
这种数据的
such data growth
增速在短期之内
might seem very impressive,
表面上看啊 非常好看
but as the regulations
但是监管呢
become more and more stringent,
已经越来越完善了
This is not a long-term solution.
这并不是什么长久之计
And it has been 8 years,
而且我们公司呢
since our company was established,
已经成立八年了
while they've only been around for five.
他们才成立五年
In this regard,
在这方面呢
we are more experienced.
我们是比较有经验的
I'm just worried
我就怕
that they might make
之前我们踩过的那些坑
the same mistake
他们还要一个一个地
as we did.
再踩一遍
Yaohui Co. was right
看来
to invest in Blue Ocean.
耀辉投蓝海是投对了
Indeed, Mr. Zhou.
对啊 周总
So I must congratulate you.
所以我得恭喜您呀
Our company
我们公司啊
has always relied on
一直是靠
solid content
扎实的内容
and strong operational capabilities
和过硬的运营能力
to survive.
在生存的
Plus,
而且现在
the investment environment
整个互联网公司
for the entire Internet industry
投资的环境和方方面面
have already passed
已经过了那个
unregulated growth phase.
野蛮生长的时期
Now, what's needed is
现在需要的是
refined operation.
精耕和细作
Mr. Zhou,
周总
I think the Xinmiao incident
我觉得这次新苗翻车啊
might be an opportunity.
也许是个机会
I propose
我们可以对它
a full acquisition.
进行一次全面的收购
So, what's your plan?
那你打算怎么做
How could you be wrong
这这么简单的题
on such a simple test?
都能错吗
Can you just think a little more?
拐个弯你就不会啦
As if you would get it right.
说得好像你会一样
Anyone can find faults.
挑错谁不会啊
Easy for you to say.
你行你上呗
Now you are talking back?
还学会顶嘴了 是吗
Listen, Li Yunjie,
李云阶 我告诉你
your good times are over.
你好日子到头了
My leave starts today.
我从今天开始休假
From now on, you are
以后你的事情
under my supervision.
都归我管
You better behave!
还就不信我治不了你了
You're on leave?
你休假了
Yes, I am,
对 我休假了
and I'll oversee
以后你的作业
your homework.
我陪你做
I don't want you. I want Dad.
我不要你 我要老爸
Dad!
爸
You heard it.
你快看呀
Mom wants to oversee my homework.
妈她要亲自抓我作业
She's haunting me,
她这不是要抓我作业
on homework and everything!
她这是要我命啊
Don't worry.
不不不 别 别着急
Here's the deal.
这样啊
I'll help
孩子学习的事
with Yunjie's study,
还是由我来抓
you enjoy your vacation,
你要休假就休假
and take care of the fetus.
好好养胎
Don't get overstressed.
不要动了胎气
Yes,
对对对
take care of your fetus.
别吓着小葡萄了
Look at you two.
你瞧你们俩那样
How do you even help?
还你抓 你怎么抓的
Her grades keep getting worse.
学习成绩一年比一年差
When was the last time
她都多长时间
she scored 100?
没考过一百分了
A 100? Impossible!
不 怎么可能有一百分
She's in grade 9,
她是初三
not grade 3.
她不是小学三年级
A 100?
一百分
She's not a genius.
她又不是学神
Well,
是吧
she shouldn't be failing either.
那也不能学成学渣呀
Failing? Not really.
学渣是不至于
We have our own
我们是有自己的
study plan,
学习规划的
right?
是不是
Yes.
对
So,
所以嘛
don't push too hard!
你就不要越级管理了
Fine,
行
I'll give you two
我就再给你们俩
one more chance.
一次机会
Make good use of it.
好好珍惜
Think carefully about your future.
未来的路到底要怎么走
Li Yunjie,
李云阶
think it over thoroughly.
你自己好好想清楚
What should we do, Dad?
怎么办呀 老爸
What should we do?
怎么办呀 爸
Keep calm.
别慌
Everything will be fine
没有什么天堂地狱
as long as you work hard.
只要你够努力
There'll be good results.
就会有好结果
But hard work doesn't always
可是努力也不一定
pay off.
有好结果呀
Still, you need to work hard first.
但首先你要努力
Swollen leg again?
腿又肿了
Let me
来
give you a massage.
我给你捏捏
You mentioned a leave.
你刚才说休假
What do you mean by that?
什么意思啊
It's just another
那就是说得好听的
expression of
说不好听的
suspension.
就是停职
But it's okay.
不过也没关系
With my experience at Xinmiao,
以我在新苗的履历
I can secure
他怎么也得给我开个
at least 80% of my salary.
百分之八十的工资
It won't affect our family.
对咱家不受影响
No,
不不不 不
I'm not asking about it.
不是这个
Why?
为什么
Why did they suspend you?
为什么他们把你停职了
The company was reported,
公司被举报了
and
然后
closed for rectification.
停业整改
They framed me up,
他们诬陷我
claiming that I reported it.
说是我举报的
I got suspended for investigation.
就停职调查呗
That's fine then.
那就没事
"Fine"? What are you saying?
什么叫那就没事啊
Didn't you just say
你不是说了吗
it was a false accusation?
诬陷 是吧
Your contributions to Xinmiao
你对新苗怎么样
are self-evident
只要你不是个瞎子
to everyone.
都看得见
You have nothing to fear.
咱们身正不怕影子歪
Let them investigate.
让他们去查
The truth will come out
这个事情
eventually.
迟早会水落石出的
Right?
对吧
I think so too.
我也觉得是
But it's still frustrating.
就是觉得挺糟心的
Actually,
本来吧
when I saw my dad
我今天看见我爸
dancing today,
能跳舞了
I was really happy.
我还挺高兴的
But before I could enjoy it,
可是还没高兴明白呢
something happened between
心心和老贾那边
Xin and Haowen.
就又出事了
What's the matter?
他们又怎么了
Haowen,
老贾
he wants to divorce Xin.
要跟心心离婚
No way.
不可能
He does.
真的
Impossible.
怎么可能
Anyone could get divorced,
全世界谁谁都可能离婚
but those two? Impossible.
就他们俩 不可能离婚
What do you mean by "anyone"?
谁谁是谁啊
Are you trying to imply us?
你是不想说咱俩啊
Nonsense,
不要瞎说嘛 我就
I'm just joking.
开个玩笑 打个比方
How could they possibly get a divorce?
他们俩怎么可能离婚
Haowen loves Xin
那老贾对心心
as much as
比我对你
I love you.
那也差不了多少
Not to mention
再说现在
they have kids now,
两个人都有孩子了
Little Watermelon, cute baby girl.
小西瓜才那么大点
How could they get a divorce?
怎么可能呢
I know, right?
我也觉得是啊
Why don't you call him
要不你给他
and ask?
打个电话问问
Right now?
现在
It's late at night.
不合适吧
Video call,
视频
see what he's up to.
看他干吗呢
He might be busy.
可能有事吧
He's calling back.
回过来了
Brother-in-law,
姐夫
no, ex-brother-in-law,
以后不能叫姐夫了
you are the younger one,
那个我比你大
so I shall call you Li Lin.
就叫你李临吧
Alright, I'm hanging up.
好了 挂了
I'm at a dinner.
我喝酒去了
Mr. Jia,
贾总
come on in.
进来啊
What a disappointment!
这个不争气的
Mr. Jia,
老贾
he is a boss.
好歹也是一个老板
There's always some socializing.
对吧 多少有点应酬
It's normal.
正常
Really?
正常吗
Brother-in-law,
姐夫
have some tea.
喝茶啊
Haowen,
浩文
I didn't ask you out for the tea.
我约你来不是来喝茶的
An honest word,
我就想问你一句话
that's all I want from you.
你也老老实实跟我说
What's going on between you two?
你们俩到底怎么回事
Why a divorce?
为什么
Brother-in-law,
姐夫
there's something
有些实话
that I can't tell you here.
是不能摆在台面上说的
It is between Xin and me.
这是我跟心心自己的事
You don't need to worry.
您就别操心了
What is this thing
什么实话
that you can't tell me?
不能摆在台面上说啊
We're family.
我们是家里人
Family doesn't keep secrets.
家里人不说实话
That's what makes us
这是规矩吗
a family!
这是道理吗
Look,
你这样好不好
Haowen,
浩文
If you have anything
你有什么外面
you can't say
你说不了的话
to other people,
就像你说的一样
something unspeakable,
上不了台面的话
you can tell me.
你跟我说
I'm not just your brother-in-law,
我不仅是你的姐夫
but also your best friend.
我还是你的好朋友
I'll help you deal with it,
我给你出主意
Okay?
行不行
Just tell me the truth.
你跟我说句实话
Meng'an is worried sick.
你姐在家都急死了
Brother-in-law,
姐夫
Xin felt it too.
心心也提出来过
Really, if two people
真的 俩人
can't get along, they should separate.
过不下去就分开
Forcing things never works.
强扭的瓜也不甜
Even if we stay married,
否则
this marriage won't be happy.
这样的婚姻也不幸福
I don't believe it.
我不信
I don't believe Xin
我不信心心提出
brought this up.
这种事情
If so, she would've said it first.
如果就是她提了
Even if she did,
就算她提了
You'd just accept it?
你就认了
Things don't work like this.
不是这样的啊
She didn't mean it.
她是跟你开玩笑 闹嘛
Isn't that what couples do
那夫妻之间不就是
messing around, arguing?
这样吵吵闹闹
Time heals everything,
这么多年也过来了
isn't it?
是不是
Haowen,
浩文啊
you're much better a husband
有时候你比我做得
than I am.
好很多
You're a role model
我都及不上你百分之十
that I look up to.
你是我的榜样啊
Just tell me,
你就告诉我
why?
为什么
What really happened?
到底发生了什么
Brother-in-law,
姐夫
like I said
有些实话
some truths
我刚才已经说了
are better sealed.
不能摆在台面说
Because, some things, if spoken,
而且有些话说出来
would hurt people.
会伤人的
This really is a family matter.
这真的是我家自己的事
Your family's matter, huh?
你家的事 是吧
I'm not a part of it, right?
就不认我了 是吧
Alright, fine!
好 没关系
We are not in-laws,
你不认我这个姐夫
no problem,
没问题
but we are still friends.
我们是不是还是朋友
Meng'an always asks me,
梦安一直问我
how are you and Haowen
你怎么和浩文
so close?
这么好呢
You're like brothers.
你俩就像哥们儿一样
I told her it was because of his character.
我跟她说我这个人看人
Nothing matters more
我不看别的
than a person's
我看这个人是不是
character.
一个好人
You are a good person.
你就是一个好人哪
After all these years...
这么多年都过来了
think about your two kids.
你俩孩子呢
Xiongxiong,
一个熊熊
and Little Watermelon,
还有个小西瓜
who is
小西瓜
just a baby.
才那么一点
Are you going to abandon them?
你不要孩子了
What about their future?
你让他们以后怎么过
No, brother-in-law,
没有 姐夫
We're just separating.
我就是分开
Getting divorced
我们就是离婚
doesn't mean
我也不会
abandoning Xin and the kids.
亏待他们娘儿仨的
Then what's the problem?
那你什么问题
Why do you want a divorce?
你要离婚呢
Do you have someone else?
你外面有人了
I don't believe so.
我认为你不是这样的人
Why won't you tell me the truth?
你说句实话能死吗
Say it.
你说
Speak up.
我等着呢 说
I can't, brother-in-law.
我不能说 姐夫
You won't say, huh?
你不说是吧
Last chance,
我再给你最后一次机会
speak up!
你说不说
Truth hurts, brother-in-law.
说实话会伤人的 姐夫
Not telling it hurts even more!
你不说实话更伤人
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
I won't ask again.
我不再问你了
This is your family's business.
这是你们家的事
But I have to tell you,
但是我告诉你
I was wrong about you.
我看错你了
You disappointed me.
太让人失望
You treat marriage
拿婚姻当儿戏
and your kids like a joke.
拿孩子不当回事
He won't even tell me!
连我都不说实话
How did Jia Haowen
贾浩文现在
end up like this?
怎么成这样了呢
What exactly
那你到底
did you tell him?
是怎么跟他说的呀
I just told him,
我就跟他说了
"You are a man.
你是一个男人
You need to be responsible.
你要有责任心
You can't just divorce on a whim."
不能够说离就离啊
And then I asked him,
我就问他了
"Do you have another woman outside?
你是不是外面有女人了
Is that why you're in such a hurry
所以才这么着急忙慌地
to get divorced?"
要离婚呢
No wonder
那你这么问他
he didn't want to tell you.
他肯定不跟你说实话呀
Then how should I ask?
那 那我怎么说啊
He's already a jerk,
他都渣男了
Why should I still be polite to him?
我还跟他客气啊
I thought you'd
这还以为你能
get something out of him.
套出什么话呢
You should have played along with him.
你这时候就应该顺着他
You know,
你知道吧
comforting him, saying
说一点鸡汤什么的
"Marriage isn't easy.
婚姻不容易啊
Tolerance is a must."
要互相包容啊
Then he could've
没准他还能
been open up to you.
跟你掏掏心窝子
Open up?
掏什么心窝子呀
You're the expert,
你这么懂
why didn't you go talk to him?
你怎么不跟他去聊呢
I'd love to, but
我倒想去来着
on what grounds?
我以什么立场啊
Why don't we hire a "paparazzi"
要不咱也找一狗仔
to follow him?
拍拍他
Track him down?
跟踪他一下
Just like the one Xin had before.
就找心心原来那个
Wait,
不对
in hindsight,
现在这么看的话
Xin was right.
心心当初是对的
Maybe that paparazzi
没准那个狗仔
was actually bought off by Haowen.
真的就被老贾买通过
Let's find another one.
咱再找一个新的
Really?
你疯啦
If you do that,
你这样做
you'll be just like Mengxin!
不是和梦心一样了吗
So what?
那怎么了
He's about to divorce my sister!
他都要跟我妹妹离婚了
Why can't I have him followed?
我找人拍他怎么了
He will be exposed!
我拍不死他
I disagree.
不靠谱
Such tactic
这种手段
won't hold up in the court.
在法律上不予承认的
Then what's your suggestion?
那你说怎么办吧
Just let me think.
你让我想想
I'll look into it.
我 打听打听
See,
这样
first,
首先啊
take good care of your sister.
你要照顾好你妹妹的
Smooth her
这个情绪
and comfort her.
安抚好
Stall for time.
再拖一拖
Let them calm down.
让他们冷静冷静
Even if they
就是万一他们
do decide to divorce,
要离婚的话
at least we know
至少咱们知道
financially,
在经济上
Haowen will support Mengxin.
老贾是不会亏待梦心的
Right?
是吧
Anyway,
反正就
we'll prepare for both results.
我们就做好两手准备呗
You're not saying anything useful.
你这不跟没说一样吗
You know what they say:
鸡汤里都说了嘛
if you can't solve a problem,
解决不了的事
leave it to time.
就交给时间嘛
So we just let it drag on?
那就这么拖着
Yes.
拖着
Look how it eats!
看它这吃着黄瓜
it really loves the cucumber.
吃得这个香啊
How about some garlic,
我再给你拍个蒜
vinegar,
再淋点醋
and maybe some sesame paste too.
再 再给你来点芝麻酱
How about that?
拌上怎么样啊
Isn't it cute?
它特别好吧
It's so adorable.
太可爱了
Here,
来
try this.
来吃这个
Eat this.
吃这个吧
Try this, try this.
吃这个 吃这个
Try mine.
来吃我这个
Let it try yours.
吃你这个
Are you full?
不吃了吗
No work today?
今天不用上班啊
It's just,
这不是
I'm,
那个
on a vacation.
休假 放假吗
Plus it's the weekend.
又是周末
I want to spend more time with the kids.
我多陪陪孩子
I'm not stressed
现在不为融资的事
about the funding anymore,
再着急了
so I want to help
所以我想帮你
you with the kids.
多分担分担
Raising kids isn't easy, right?
带孩子不容易吧
Yes, in the past,
是 这以前吧
I didn't spend much time with them.
我带孩子带得少
But in these past few days,
这几天
I've been with them all the time,
跟她们在一块儿啊
and I'm exhausted.
累死我了
I just realized how tired you were,
我才知道你有多累
back then.
当时
It's been tough for you all these years.
这么多年你辛苦了啊
From now on, when you work,
以后你工作啊
I'll help take care of the kids.
我 我帮你带孩子
Not easy to be a good father.
当个好爸爸更不容易
Then, I'll try to be a good husband.
我 更想当个好丈夫
Mr. Xu,
老许
Your older brother is calling again.
大哥又打电话来了
What should we do?
怎么办
Tell him I'm not here.
你说我不在
Are you sure?
不在啊
I'll tell him this way.
那 那我接了啊
Hello, big brother.
大哥
Why did you take so long to answer,
你怎么才接电话呢
Sister-in-law?
弟妹啊
I didn't hear it.
没 没 没听见
Household things, you know.
忙着呢 不家里事多吗
Not busier than me, I'm sure.
那你还能有我忙啊
Well...
这这 这这
Where's my brother?
我老弟呢
I want to speak to him.
我要跟他说话
He's here.
在呢 在呢 在呢
Give the phone to him.
你让他接电话
He's in the toilet.
上厕所了
He's always in there!
他屎尿咋这么多呢
Every time I call,
我 我一打电话
he's either without his phone
不是没带手机
or in the toilet.
就是上厕所
What's up with him?
怎么了他
Hurry up, let him answer the phone.
快点让他接电话吧
Slide the phone under the door
你从门缝给他塞进去
to him.
把电话
Just wait.
那那 你等会儿
Wait a moment, he...
你等会儿啊 他
Hurry up.
快点
Who is it?
谁呀
Wait a sec.
你 你等会儿
See, he's out.
出来了 出来了
Take a look.
你看 你看 你看
You see?
你看
Here he is.
这不是吗
My goodness!
我天
You really...
你可真是 你呀
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了你
Why didn't you pick up my calls?
我怎么打电话你不接啊
No...
没
No... no...
没 没有
What's wrong?
你怎么了
Tell me what's wrong.
你跟哥说你怎么了
I'm fine.
没怎么呀
Your mouth looks a bit crooked.
不是 你嘴怎么有点歪呢
Say something.
你给我说句话
Alright.
好了
Oh my goodness, you...
我天哪你
Why didn't you tell me?
你怎么不跟我说呢你
I'll come over tomorrow.
我明天过去啊
No.
不
Wait for me.
你等着我
Is my mouth crooked?
我嘴歪了吗
No.
不是
You were just...
你刚才
You were just nervous
你刚才紧张了
When you get nervous, maybe...
你这一紧张可能
He's been scared of him since I was a kid.
我从小就怕他
Why is it?
不是
He's so far away.
你这隔大老远
Why are you scared of him?
你怕他干吗呀 这
What should we do?
那 那怎么办
He's coming over tomorrow.
明天大哥过来了
Let him come.
来来吧
It's been so long since I last saw him.
这么长时间没看见他了
What time is it?
几点了
It's past 4 PM.
这 下午四点多
Let's go,
走吧
take me to the acupuncture.
赶紧陪我去针灸
Where are we going?
干吗去
To the acupuncture.
针灸啊 今天
But,
我说你
it's near their closing time.
现在人家都快下班了
What?
什么
I scheduled it for 4 PM yesterday.
我昨天约的就是四点
Let's go.
走吧
Did you have fun yesterday?
昨天开心吗
Celebrating the kids' birthday,
陪孩子过生日
I was really happy.
当然开心了
Was it Yu Hai's idea?
这是于海的安排吗
No, it's me.
当然是我安排的
First,
一来呢
I invited him to discuss
我约他来谈一谈
the future of Blue Ocean.
蓝海未来的发展
Second,
二来呢
you could celebrate the kids' birthday,
让你能跟孩子过个生日
giving you a surprise.
给你个惊喜
So you won't be distracted
免得你工作时候
while working.
心有旁骛
Am I a good boss to you now?
你说我这个老板好不好
I think I should
我都觉得我
change my name
不应该叫周耀
to Mr. Thoughtful.
我应该叫周到
So thoughtful of you.
太周到了
Thank you, boss.
谢谢老板啊
You're welcome.
不客气
But have you ever
但是你这个举动吧
considered that Yu Hai
你就没有想过
might misunderstand?
于海 会误会
What misunderstanding?
误会 什么误会
Ever since our divorce,
从我们离婚以后
he's been hoping for us back together.
他一直抱有复婚的幻想
If we really got back together,
我要是真复婚了
do you think
你觉得
it would
会不会对我的工作
affect my work?
有影响啊
I really hadn't thought about that.
这我还真没想过
I just wanted to surprise you,
我就是想给你个惊喜
so I did.
所以就答应了
But I'm not worried.
不过我不担心
You are not that foolish
你不会傻到刚离婚
to consider a remarriage, aren't you?
就又复婚吧
Wanzhen,
婉真
I just want
我其实就想
to be a little nicer to you.
对你好一点
What do you mean?
你什么意思呀
Sounds creepy.
你别吓唬我啊
No,
不
it's just a boss being nice
对给自己能挣钱的员工
to
好一点
a competent employee
不是每一个老板
who profits the company.
必须的自我修养吗
Let's go out for a walk.
我们出去转转
We stay indoors long enough.
不在屋里待了
It's stifling.
闷得慌
Yes, it's stifling,
你说我们闷得慌
Let's not stay indoors.
不在屋里待了
We'll go out for a walk.
出去转转
Be careful on the way.
路上小心点啊
Don't worry.
放心吧啊
We'll be back soon.
一会儿就回来
Auntie's back!
姨回来啦
Going out?
出去啊
We're going out for a walk.
我们出去逛逛
Go finish your homework first,
你 你先去做作业去啊
Xiongxiong.
熊熊
Xin,
心心
can you call Haowen?
你给浩文打个电话呗
What for?
干吗
Your uncle
你爸的大哥
is coming over
你大伯
tomorrow.
明天过来
He needs Haowen's car
用那个浩文的车
to pick him up from the rail station.
到高铁站 接一下
And maybe take him for a tour.
顺便逛一逛
Call him.
你给他打吧
Why don't you tell him directly?
你直接跟他说
I want you to make the call.
我就是让你打
Let you two speak again.
这不给你个由头吗
I don't know what happened.
这怎么回事啊
Haowen always soothed you well
那以前你们俩吵架
whenever there was a quarrel.
那浩文都能给你哄回去
What happened this time?
这次怎么了呀
What is this silent treatment for?
怎么还打上冷战了呀
This is between me and him.
我跟他两个人的事
Just leave us alone.
你别管了